the Poles did not in any way force Hitler to
поляки никак не вынуждали Гитлера
attack, to attack or not to attack - this is
нападать нападать или не нападать - это
Hitler’s decision and not forced. Polyakov
решение Гитлера а не вынуждено Поляков
Putin is simply justifying his
Путин просто на весь мир оправдывая своё
attack on Ukraine to the whole world, he says
нападение на Украину он да рассказывает
that just like we were forced to
что так же само как вот нас вынудили
attack, and also Hitler was forced to
напасть Да также и Гитлера вынудили
attack. He put himself in  on the same side
напасть Он поставил себя в одну сторону
with Hitler,
с Гитлером
let's talk normally nene I,
давайте нормально поговорим нене Я
on the contrary, I'm only for normal communication,
наоборот я только за нормальное общение
on the contrary, I get more stress when it
как раз я наоборот больше стрессу когда
starts, you know, I see you have
начинает прям знаеш я смотрю у вас вот
this imperial flag I like it from the
этот имперский флаг Мне нравится с
imperial  talk yes you are 18 years old there are
имперца разговаривать да вам 18 лет есть
20 Even there is super Can you tell me
20 Даже есть супер А можете рассказать
Why you hanged this particular flag Well what does
Почему вы именно этот флаг повес Ну что
it mean to you the imperial flag Yes I
он для вас означает имперский флаг Да я
can explain what it means to me
могу объяснить что он для меня означает
This can be said to be part of my history
Это можно сказать часть моей истории
in general part of my country with
вообще часть моей страны с
stories that are rare when  Russian empires were
стори редки при российский империи были
aristocratic kings, or
царями аристократами или
But mine, after all, Yes, from people like M to say
А мои всё-таки Да из таких как М сказать
from serfs, I understand, yes,
из крепостных прои происходи понял да А
but look, it turns out, uh, in this country,
чем-то смотри получается э в этой стране
which was the Russian Empire, uh, yours
которая была Российская империя ээ ваши
ancestors were absolutely powerless, they
предки были абсолютно бесправные их
could have been exchanged for a purebred dog,
могли поменять на породистую собаку
for example, lost at cards Yes But all this
например проиграть в карты Да Во а вся э
property All power belonged to
имущество Вся власть принадлежала
a small layer of aristocracy Why
небольшой прослойке аристократии Почему
then are you happy about
же вы тогда радуетесь
this empire No, it’s not that I’m happy in
этой империи Нет не то чтобы я радуюсь в
terms of the fact that like Wow, how cool I am
плане того что типа Вау как круто я
and not  well, look cool, first of all, a
и не ну круто смотрите во-первых
beautiful combination of colors, that's what
красивое сочетание цветов вот сог что
was cool in that country, your ancestors
круто в той стране было вот ваши предки
lived simply as serfs, they could be
жили просто как крепостные их могли
exchanged for a dog and sold  flog for
обменять на собаку да продать выпороть
example ho with them They could have done Yes, in the World Cup the
например хо с ними Могли сделать Да в ЧМ
joke of this country was, you
прикол этой страны был
know, the concept was generally there before 1867
понимаете концепция вообще была до 1867
or 62. That is, when serfdom was abolished,
либо 62 года То есть когда отменили
such as it is, approximately 1900,
такая каком это приблизительно 1900
which is not
какой нет
1867 or 18, but I won’t tell you for sure Yes, the
1867 либо 18 хо я вам точно не назову Да
troika was abolished and  what happened to
была тройка отменили и что случилось с
your you there after that, well, the serfs
вашим вы там после этого ну у крепостных
got the opportunity to learn and be
Появилась возможность выку и быть
free because look no,
свободными потому что смотрите нет
initially Russia took it from whom?
изначально Россия же с кого при брала с
England, France, that is, such
Англией Францией то есть странами такими
coalition countries, there were only slaves there and there
коалиционных рабы были только там были и
were also subjects there, where where where in
подданные там тоже были где где где в
Britain there were fish, well, were you in a colony
Британии были рыбы ну вы что были колоне
from where did you transport just the same? Well, that’s
откуда вы возили как раз таки Ну исто
where in Britain In what century there
Где в Британии В каком столетии в
were
Британии были
slaves in Britain Yes, everything is different  management is called
рабы Да всё сво управление называется
itself now Let me formulate it
самой сейчас Дайте вам сформулирую
correctly so as not to
правильно чтобы не
lie Great Britain itself
наврать сама сама по себе Великобритания
was a colonial
была колониальной
country, so let’s start like In
страной давай так давай начнём типа В
what millennium did
каком тысячелетии появилась
Great Britain appear before ours  era Let me give
Великобритания до нашей эры Давай так я
you
тебе
a hint, look, look this century
подскажу смотри смотри тье столетие до
BC or this century AD
нашей эры или тье столетие нашей эры
When Great
Когда появилась
Britain appeared I think not that not this
Великобритания Я думаю не тот не этот
answer why I think I think maybe
ответ почему я думаю я думаю возможно
maybe somewhere because look
возможно где-то потому смотрите
initially estra verita was it was
изначально эстра верита было это
Anglo-Saxon there were such peoples at first
англосаксонские были сначала такие
and then after that some kind of
народы и потом после этого какая-то
confederation was created, just the same,
произвела конфедерация как раз таки
where Ireland was forcibly
которая где ирландию насильно Шотландию
annexed by Scotland, too, forcibly. They came here to
присоединили тоже на сильно Они же сюда
sabotage this
против этого саботировать
what century was the
в каком веке в Британии был
slave system in Britain Well in the Middle
рабовладельческий строй Ну в средние
Ages Well for example in what century Well century century
века Ну например в какой век Ну век век
in Britain Well and you have some other
в Британии Ну а у вас какая-то другая
point I I First time I hear that
точка Я я Впервые слышу что
[music]
[музыка]
slave and again Well tell me
рабовладельческое и ещё раз Ну скажи ещё
again where it was
раз где было
slave how  just
рабовладельческой как раз таки
where Well, you say so where Well Well In what
где Ну вы так говорите где Ну Ну В каком
century where not yet Look no ra look
столетие где не ещ Смотри не ра смотрите
rap is
рап это
when this person is the property of
когда этот человек есть собственностью
another person Yes and another person
другого человека Да и другой человек
can dispose of his life for example
может распоряжаться его жизнью например
sell  like property Yes there to
продать как имущество Да там там
exchange And so on when this happened in
обменять И так дальше когда такое было в
Britain No well, that is, it turns out,
Британи Не ну то есть получается
look if the English invader is with
смотрите если английский интервент при
you Yes, let's say so, the colonialists are
же са Да скажем так колонизаторы и
simply in charge of the lives of Indians
распоряжаются просто жизнью индусов
who Well, don't look again, look,
которые Ну не ещё раз смотри смотри
Come on, So come on, Look, if you
Давай давай Так давай Смотреть если ты
say  about the seizure of some territories, the
говоришь про захват каких-то территорий
Indians were not slaves, the Indians were not
индусы не были рабами индусов не
sold, as for example when Britain
продавали как например в когда Британия
controlled the territory of India. Yes, the
контролировала территорию Индии Да у
Indians had more rights than you did,
индусов было прав больше чем у тебя
your ancestors  in the Russian Empire Well,
твоих предков в Российской империи Ну
you know, I’m not from the Indians, the Indians weren’t
знаете я из не индусы индусы не были не
these
были этими
slaves. Well, it’s possible, maybe they weren’t
рабами Ну это можно ра может они не были
slaves, but they weren’t happy either because the
рабами но тоже они не были счастливы от
English hand put pressure on them and
того что английская рука давила на них и
gave them some rights because I
Уля их в некоторых правах потому что я
also know  look again again Come on, let's
зна ещё раз ещё раз смотри Дава давай
start, that means we put an end to yes, uh,
начнём значит ставим точку да э
slaveholding, if it wasn't, then
рабовладельческого если не было то
okay, I'll check this information
хорошо я проверю эту информацию сегодня
tonight, I got it, I got it, Dawa, Let's
вечером понял понял Дава Дава давай
look further, like you're saying that
смотрим дальше типа ты говоришь что
Russia  took an example from Britain. I
Россия брала пример с Британии Я что-то
can’t understand something. Russia
не могу понять Россия пример крепостное
took the example of serfdom from Britain or what. Well,
право взяла с Британии или как Ну это
no, why if you already said that Well,
Нет почему если вы сказали уже что Ну
as you said that there were no slaves. So it turns out
как вы сказали что раб не было Значит
no. Look, your ancestors are from
получается нет А смотри твои предки С
which province. From which
какой губернии С каких
regions  Now I’ll tell you,
областей сейчас вам скажу
yes, from the Belarusian lands
да с белорусских земель
From which
С каких
Belarusians in the region of Belarus, then
белору в районе Белоруси то
most likely the
что бре скорее всего
bre understood that you have nothing to do with the Russians at all,
бре понял то ты к русским вообще не
why
имеешь никакого отношения почему
PP You know when Brest even fell
же ПП Ты знаешь когда Брест вообще попал
into the Russian Empire Well, the breen
в Российскую империю Ну брен изначально
didn’t initially  was
не был
Vova in general
вообще Вова
ancestors you should know the history of your ancestors
предки ты ж историю своих предков должен
yes In what century is the
да В каком веке примерно известно о
existence of Brest known approximately From what century
существование Бреста С какого века
exactly when was it in the Russian
именно когда он именно был в Российской
Empire Or not at all at all Well
империи Или вообще не вообще вообще Ну
generally quite old Well
вообще достаточно такой старенький Ну
old Well old this is approximately the
старин Ну старенький это приблизительно
10th
X век
century  around Well, I think a century and a century Well, somewhere
се около Ну думаю век век Ну где-то
around this Yes, in the region of the century, the birch bark
около этом Да в районе века берестя
city of Berestye Yes, it was one of the
город Берестье Да это был один из
most famous cities of the Polyans of the Polyan
известнейших городов Полян племени Полян
Slavic tribe But the Polyans lived on the
славянских Да вот поляне проживали на
territory of modern Ukraine and
территории современной Украины и
Belarus  it was just the Slavs, but
Белоруси это как раз славяне были да
that’s what it is, for example, the Berestey union, you
вот что такое например берестейска уния
know, the Berestey union, which was in
знаешь берестейская уния которая была в
the city, I don’t know what birch bark is,
городе не я знаю что такое береста
for example, it’s
например
not this bere, which is from a birch Well, yes,
не это бере которая от берёзы Ну да а
namely
именно
the events that were good, let’s do
событиях которое было хорошо давай
this What kind of people Yes
так Какие народы Да
inhabited Brest
населяли Брест
and its environs  and from time
и его окрестности и спокон
immemorial the Poles Well, let me just tell you in
веков поляки Ну давайте вам просто скажу
one general Slavic population groups the
одним целом славянские группы населения
Eastern Slavs What
восточные славяне Какие
exactly were the Russians, Ukrainians,
конкретно опреде были русские украинцы
Belarusians and  Poles means there were no Russians there, the
белорусы и поляки значит русских там не
main population of Brest and its
основное население Бреста и его
environs were Ukrainians and Belarusians, the
окрестности - это украинцы и белорусы
majority were Ukrainians, by the way. Yes,
большинство было кстати украинцев Да
if you look at the last census of the Russian
если ты посмотришь перепись Российской
Empire. Yes, in terms of language, yes, they
империи последней Да по языковому да это
were Ukrainians.
украинцы были
Now this is what country
Вот теперь такое В какие в какую страну
Brest was included in historically. Brest which country.  entered Well,
Брест Брест какую страну входил Ну
before which countries before this
раньше каким странам до того как вот это
flag appeared
флаг появился
in your country? Yes, your ancestors did not live in the
у тебя Да у тебя же предки жили не в
Russian Empire. And in which countries did they
Российской империи А в каких странах они
live? Well, maybe then the Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth
жили Ну может быть тогда реч посполита а
to the
до Речи
Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth to the Polish-
Посполитой до Речи
Lithuanian Commonwealth now date I’ll think I’ll remember the
Посполитой сейчас дате подумаю вспомню
Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth we had territories damn it
ре посполиты у нас были территории блин
Remind me I won’t even say I won’t even Remind
Напомните не скажу даже не Напомните
Tell me Well, okay How did the territory
Скажите Ну хорошо Как территория
of Belarus there, for example, get into the
Белорусии там например попала в речь
Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth
посполитую
100% 100% with some
100% 100% при каких-то
Bosnia Grand Duchy of Lithuania
Босния Великое княжество Литовское
heard something-  then yes yes yes Everything everything in
слышал что-то да да да Всё всё во полное
its full name Grand Duchy of Lithuanian
его название Великое княжество Литовское
Russian and  Zhemaitis so you know about him I don’t know so when the Mongols Yes captured Rus' what happened next about 300 or 200 years they took tribute just from the Russians no no no stop stop stop wait let’s not take it like that you say 300 or How many years in what century captured Kyiv Which Kyiv was captured and no Mongols Mongols like Which Kyiv is one Kyiv Mongols in what century captured Kyiv They didn’t capture it
русское и жемайтис так что ты знаешь про
seriously Well, because as Well they explained to us, like the principality was so scattered and they captured them one by one, what I don’t remember is that some kind of speech was captured in the 10th century at the end of the century when the Mongols captured Kyiv Yes, the question is In what year and by Who liberated Kyiv, where the hell did he run away from, and such a beautiful emperor was pitifully cut short from Brest; his, his ancestors were, damn it, in Rus', which had nothing to do with Muscovy. In the great  in the Principality
никакого отношения В великом княжестве
of Lithuania there were Russian borders of Matis in the
литовском были русско меже Матис в Речи
Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth Yes, and he’s some kind of rag of the
Посполитой Да и он какую-то тряпку
Russian Empire, where the hell his
Российской империи весит где блин его
ancestors were just Oh damn, let’s move
предки были просто Ой блин так Поехали
on How am I Okay Okay I’m not quarreling
дальше Как де я Окей окей я не ссорится
e Yes Okay Russia Russia Okay
е Yes Окей Раша Раша Окей я учить
I don’t want to learn Russian  quarrel I love I
русский я не хотеть ссориться я любить я
don't don't quarrel
не не не ругаться
nono America and Russia should be
ноно Америка и Раша должны
friends I learn
дружить я учить
Russian speak bad my teacher  Masha from
русский плохо говорить моя тичер Маша из
Novosibirsk She lives now in California
Новосибирск Она жит сейчас в калифор
I and She teaches me and
я и Она учит меня и
others the Russian language I want to come to
другие русский язык Я хотеть приехать в
Russia from what
Раша из какой
city Bryansk Bryansk is this
город Брянск Брянск это
where is this Bryansk region Well where is
где это Брянская область Ну где это
Moscow
моско
why go
чего ещ
to university again to study
раз в университет учиться
and what
да какой
specialty is construction of
специальность строительство
highways to
автомобильных
build
строить
roads  there are many roads in the
дорогинь много дороги
country, Masha says that from her
страна Маша говорит что из её
Novosibirsk it’s several thousand kilometers to go to Mosco,
Новосибирск ехать в Моско несколько
I understand, yes, I don’t quarrel with Russia, I want to
понял да я я не ругаться с Раша я хоте
come and see this big country,
приехать посмотреть этот большая страна
lake  Baikal
озеро Байкал
is yours
это у вас
yes and you What course is it now
да а вы Какой курс сейчас это
va and you by the way Russia is interested in learning
ва а вы кстати Раша учить
English about me
английский о мне
My Russian looks funny
интересно Мой русский смешно выглядит
or
или
but
но
I find it
я мне
difficult to speak I make a mistake when
сложно говорить я ошибка делать когда
you tell me Inter how people from Russia
говори вы мне Интере как люди из Раша
speak English You can count
говорить по английски Можете посчитать
from o  up to 20 in English
от о до 20 по английски
Alvin
Элвин
further this is not this already 20 with something here
дальше это не это уже 20 с чем-то вот
after 10 after 10
после 10 после 10
Alvin Well, it’s still bad to know Russian Let’s
Элвин Ну плохо ещё русский знать Давайте
aisky Let’s try again from One to
айский Давай ещё раз попробуй от One до
20 from  about up to 20
20 от о до 20
in English up to only I can Come on up to 20
по-английски до только могу Давай до 20
Try everything
Попробуй всё
evin this way you can teach yes, I’m sorry, but here’s
эвин так можно учить да извиняюсь а вот
the question And that’s why you have a hundred here ukra
вопрос А вот почему у вас стот вот укра
connected
соединено
Ukra I was interested in talking to them
Укра мне интересно было я с ними
about the war the same way
говорить о война также как с вами
I talk to you But with  I speak Russian to them,
говорить я Но с ними по-русски я
I learn Russian and talk about the
говорить я учить русский и говорить о
war with Ukraine and I know that there are
война с Украина и я знаю что есть
Americans who are fighting in Ukraine and
Американ которые воевать в Украина и
asking them or whether they are fighting there
спрашивать их или они воевать там
[music]
[музыка]
understood And you How are you  to fight Ukraine with
понял А вы Как вы воевать Украина с
Russia, are you military, are you shooting or are you
рашей вы вы военные стрелять или вы
just learning to
только учиться
learn to shoot in Ukraine Are you not
учиться стрелять по Украина А вы вы не
afraid that they will take you to war?
боятся что вас взять на война
Why won’t they take us
почему не возьмут нас
Why,
Почему
firstly, and secondly, there
во-первых во-вторых
is no mobilization And how do you feel about Vladimir
нет А как вы относиться к Владимир
Putin Good good
Путин Хорошо хорошо
Why  and you’re like, you don’t support it,
Почему а ты типа что не поддерживаешь
it’s
это
his life, because the leader is the
его пожи пото что лидер вопервых
leader first Why Leader You have oil gas
лидер Почему Лидер Вы имеете нефть газ
gold Diamond And you live poorly, you live
золото Алмаз А живёте бедно живёте
poorly, we live poorly How much do you have
бедно мы бедно живём Сколько у тебя
scholarship 45 45000
стипендия 45 45000
your teacher's
у твой преподаватель
salary I'm now I'm looking at the
зар я сейчас я посмотреть стипендия
Bryansk scholarship look So come on, check it out,
Брянск посмотреть Так давай давай чекай
check it out, the
чекай
Bruns scholarship is
бранс
rubles, well, what about you How much do you have? Come on,
руб ну а у вас У вас сколько давай дава
okay, I'll work as a teacher of
О'кей я работать э преподаватель
anthropology at the University of
антропологии в университет
Sacramento My salary is small,
Сакраменто Мой зарплата небольшой 99.000
$99,000 a month  this is for your money,
долларов в месяц это на ваш деньга
900,000 rubles per
900.000 руб в
month. Well,
месяц Ну
now wait, wait, let me  I’ll look for
Сейчас подожди стой Дай я посмотрю
a second, look at the salary of University of
секунду посмотри зарплата University
Sacramento
Sacramento
now 53,150 dollars Now a second
сейчас 53 150 долларов Сейчас секунду
[music]
[музыка]
l Well, everything, everything,
л Ну всё всё
everything, look, Why do you live in poverty in Russia,
всё так посмотри Почему вы в России жить
having gas, gold,
бедно имея газ золото
Diamond, I don’t know
Алмаз не знаю
[music]
[музыка]
which is mine
какая моя
or Why why For example, a person in
либо Почему почему Например человек в
Europe is small, Estonia, life is better  what are
Европа маленький Эстония жить лучше чем
you doing in Russia? How do you say to this that this is a
вы в Раша А как ты скажешь вот на это
balance, this is your brokerage account in the
это баланс это твой счёт брокерский в
game
игре
game Think further uh Just wait Here come on
игре Думай дальше э Вот подожди Вот
Well look if  you had
давай Хорошо смотри если б у тебя был
100,000 dollars You weren’t sitting there just now,
100.000 долларов Ты этой сейчас не сидел
why
а почему
explain it, wait, wait, let’s start with
объясни вот стой стой Давай начнём с
that, you want to come to Russia Yes,
того ты хочешь приехать в Россию Да
yes, now you’re saying that it’s Well, what’s
yes вот ты сейчас говоришь что это Ну а
the point of coming here? Yes, I’m studying,
смысл тебе сюда ехать Вот Yes я изучать
I’m a professor of anthropology, I’m studying and
я профессор антропология я изучать анд
phages  and
фагов и сре
environment Well understood What kind of car do you have,
обитания Хорошо понял Какая у тебя
let’s say this is how much it costs in
машина допустим вот сколько она стоит на
Russian rubles if of course you
российских рублях если у тебя конечно
have one Okay I have a Range Rover car
она есть Окей У меня машина Range Rover
if you know I took it because I
если ты знать это я взял потому что мне
need to drive around  different road in the field
нужно ездить по разные дорога в поле
explore different
исследовать разные
anfa good What phone do you have Which
анфа хорошо Какой у тебя телефон Какой
phone can you show Or are you using it
телефон можеь показать Или ты с него
I have a regular
у меня обычный
Samsung and
Samsung и
that lice I know lice you want a phone
что вша я знать вша вы хотеть телефон
for you that’s something wow wow yes no no
для вас это что-то вауу вау да не не
why like let’s say you’re for  a month
почему типа вот допустим ты за месяц
you earn almost a million rubles from Russian rubles
зарабатываешь на российских рублях почти
Yes, let’s say How much
Да вот допустим Сколько у тебя сейчас
balance do you have on your card now? I’ll explain to you the thing is
баланс на карте я объяснить тебе дело в
that you
том что вы
don’t understand Where can people spend so much
не понимать Куда люди могут деть столько
money? We just live in a normal house,
деньги мы жить просто в нормальный дом
not in this, how much do you have?  you live here in
не в вот как Вы сколько у вас тут жить в
this How many of you people live in one
этот Сколько вас человек жит в одной
room three people in one room
комнате три человека в одной комнате
or if it Show me this room I’m
или если это Покажи мне эту комнату мне
interested And I’m on a laptop I’m like
интересно А я на ноутбуке я типа ну типа
well I can’t show you at all Turn
никак тебе не смогу показать Покрути
twist the
покрутить
laptop what else besides the bed is your
ноутбук что ещё кроме кровати есть ваша
room
комната
a refrigerator  refrigerator cabinets the furniture is all
холодильник холодильник шкафы мебель вся
new But here you are now Show me your house I
новая Но вот ты сейчас Покажи свой дом я
want to somehow show something
чтоб каким-то показывать что-то
with such a conversation You can go
с таким разговором Ты можешь пойти
just because
просто потому что
you’re just
ты вы просто
about small really googled salaries in
о малой реально загуглил зарплаты в
America
Америке
Ty Hello hello What interesting things are
Тай Привет здравствуйте Что интересного
you discussing today
обсуждаете сегодня
I ask why Putin justifies
спрашиваю почему Путин оправдывает
Hitler, where does he justify him? But he
Гитлера где он его оправдывает А вот он
has already seen the whole world in an interview and is
в интервью уже весь мир видел да
already discussing what Putin said in an interview with this
обсуждает уже что Путин в интервью этому
Carlson or Blame the Pooh Yes, he said that
карлсону или вини пуху Да рассказал что
Hitler also attacked Poland in
Гитлер тоже напал на Польшу в рить дем
2009 because Poland forced it
году потому что Польша вынудила потому
because it was intractable  justification for
что была несговорчивый оправдание
Nazism,
нацизма
this is Carlson, he said this, no, this is Putin,
это Карлсон сказал это нет это Путин
look. If you want, I’ll play a fragment for you.
смотри Хочешь тебе включу фрагмент Ну
Come on, surprise, listen,
давай удиви послушаешь
let’s
давай
look, this part was the territory  was given to
смотри эта часть территория была отдана
Poland and the territory was given to Poland and
Польше и территория была отдана Польше и
instead of Danzig the city of Gdansk appeared,
вместо данцига появился город Гданьск
here is Hitler. The
вот Гитлер
Poles refused to beg to give it up peacefully,
Упрашивать отдать мирно поляки
this part of the territory was
отказались эта часть территории была
given to
отдана
Poland. Well, the Poles
Польше
didn’t give an excuse for the failure and
оправдание невали поляки не отдали и
that’s why Yes, and that’s why they attacked, it’s
поэтому Да и поэтому типа напали
not good, I’ll get them now in a
намал не хорошо я те сейчас полный
full
достану полнее
minute.  you're
минуту раз ты такой
not like that Look, you're just now I'll
нет Смотри ты просто сейчас я тебе
tell you now come on now just don't
сейчас скажу давай сейчас только не
waste
сливай
baby now we'll take it completely
малыш сейчас мы полне эте возьмём
so now now now
так сейчас сейчас
now the Poles forced  they played too hard and
сейчас поляки вынудили они заигрались и
forced Hitler to start the Second World
вынудили Гитлера начать Вторую Мировую
War, it was with him that the Poles forced them
Войну именно с ним поляки вынудили они
to play and forced Hitler to start the
заигрались и вынудили Гитлера начать
Second World War with them. Why did the
Вторую Мировую Войну именно с них Почему
war begin on September 1,
И началась война 1 сентября тридцать
1939, it was with Poland that it
девятого года именно с Польшей она
turned out to be intractable; Hitler had
оказалась несговорчивый Гитлеру ничего
no choice in implementing his plans
не оставалось при реализации его планов
to start  it was from Poland that the Poles forced them.
начать именно с Польши поляки вынудили
They played too much, that is, look, uh, he’s
Они заигрались то есть смотри ээ он
an excuse, that’s an excuse Yes, because the
оправдание вот оправдание Да потому что
Poles are to blame because the Poles
что поляки виноваты потому что поляки
forced Yes  the Poles forced, look, he
вынудили Да поляки вынудили смотри он
said clearly, the Poles forced Yes, it’s
сказал чётко поляки вынудили Да не
not Hitler, it’s not Hitler’s fault, look, but the
Гитлер не Гитлер виноват смотри а а
Poles forced Yes, because they were
поляки вынудили Да потому что были
intractable,
несговорчивый
that is, look, your president justifies
то есть смотри ваш президент оправдывает
Hitler’s actions and accuses the Poles that
действия Гитлера и обвиняет Поляков что
they made Hitler’s plan. So
они Гитлера был план сделали Так что
Hitler decided to start fulfilling his clan
Гитлер решил начать исполнить свой клан
with  Poland no, the Poles forced him to attack
с Польше нет поляки вынудили напасть
Look, why Hitler attacked Poland,
Смотри из-за чего Гитлер напал на Польшу
as far as I remember, some disputed
насколько я помню какие-то спорные
territories, well, that is, the Poles forced
территории ну то есть поляки вынудили
him or
его или
Hitler no Hitler  I just found a reason,
Гитлер нет Гитлер просто нашл повод
let’s see, Hitler found a reason
давай так то смотри Гитлер нашёл повод
or the Poles forced
или поляки вынудили
Hitler Hitler found a reason You see everything, that
Гитлера Гитлер нашёл повод Всё видишь То
is, the world doesn’t say the Poles forced Yes,
есть мир не говорит поляки вынудили Да
because then the Poles would be to blame, they
потому что тогда бы виноваты были поляки
forced Yes And Putin directly Putin
они вынудили Да А Путин прямо Путин
directly I just showed you you
прямо я тебе только что показал ты
said where  - where did I give it to you? Listen, yes,
говорил где-где я тебе дал Послушай Да
he clearly says the Poles
он Чётко говорит поляки
forced him. What is forced?
вынудили Что такое вынуждены вынужден
It means you have no other
это ты значит у тебя нету других
options. You simply have to
вариантов Ты просто уже обязан это
do it. Yes, the Poles didn’t force Hitler in any way.  to
сделать Да так вот поляки никак не
attack, to attack or
вынуждали Гитлера нападать нападать или
not to attack is Hitler’s decision and not
не нападать - это решение Гитлера а не
forced. Polyakov Putin is simply
вынужден Поляков Путин просто на весь
justifying his attack on Ukraine to the whole world,
мир оправдывая своё нападение на Украину
he says that just like
он да рассказывает что так же само как
we were forced to attack. And also
вот нас вынудили напасть Да также и
Hitler was forced to attack. He put
Гитлера вынудили напасть Он поставил
himself on the same side as Hitler on  one
себя в одну сторону с Гитлером на один
level absolutely It’s not I who came up with this
уровень абсолютно Это не я придумал это
om
ом
with in this and the story for the whole world so
с в это и рассказа на весь мир так
the question is Why are you a country justify
вопрос Почему вы страна оправдайте
Hitler by saying that he was forced to remove the
Гитлера говоря что его вынудили снимаете
blame from him Oh how you twisted one
вину с него О как ты и скрутил один
person so in the country  This person
человек поэтому на в страна Этот человек
represents your country, this is your
представляет вашу страну это ваш
president, if he does not reflect the will of
президент если он не отображает волю
the people, say Hey hello, you are discrediting the memory of
народа сказать Эй алло ты порочит память
our grandfathers who fought against
наших дедов которые воевали против
Hitler. Well, why are you extinguished, baby, didn’t say
Гитлера Ну что ты потух малыш не сказал
why are you extinguished, the baby is not extinguished,
что ж ты потух малыш не потух потух
something has gone out, your eyes have become gloomy and so on
что-то глазки уже невесёлые стали да так
Why does your president justify Hitler,
Почему ваш президент оправдывает Гитлера
justify the attack on Poland, the
оправдывает нападение на Польшу
outbreak of World War II and
развязывание Второй мировой войны и и
twisted the fact so once again the fact look No
скрутил факт так ещё раз факт смотри Нет
listen again as I saw yay come on as I
ещё раз послушай как увидел яй давай как
saw Come on  the Poles did what gave
увидел Давай поляки сделали то что дало
Hitler a cart they did an attack at the beginning of
Гитлеру воз они сделали напасть нача
their plan if So what the
своего плана сли Так что сделали
Poles did Hitler got the
поляки Гитлер получил
opportunity what the Poles did what
возможность то что поляки сделали что
gave him this reason what what the
дала ему этот повод какой что сделали
Poles did gitr should have at this moment what the
поляки гитр должен был в этот момент что
Poles did gave a reason what
сделали поляки дали повод какой
disputed territory did not agree  once
спорный территории не согласи е раз ещ
again, look, there were no disputed
раз смотри никаких спорных смотри
territories, look, there were no disputed territories as
никаких спорных территорий не было в
a result of the First World War Yes, there were
результате первой мировой войны Да были
clearly peace treaties, all
чётко мирными договорами установлены все
borders were established, there were no disputed territories,
границы никаких спорных территорий не
no one argued with anyone, there is a peace
было Никто с кем не спорил есть мирный
treaty  Versailles Yes, where everything is clearly
договор Версальский Да где всё чётко
spelled out Yes, some
прописано Да тут появляются какие-то
guys with mustaches appear here, Dolph, just like
чуваки усатые Дольф так же как вот
this Putin, for example, appears and says
например этот Путин появляется и говорит
Oh listen, we don’t like peaceful ones
О слушайте нам не нравится мирные
earlier Give it to us, the Poles say
бы раньше Отдайте нам это поляки говорят
damn it, these are our territories, there
блин это наши территории вот мирный
is a peace treaty,
договор есть
but don’t Ugh  this topic, how are you now,
да не Уй от этой темы как ты сейчас
the analogy with Putin is absolutely also
аналогию с Путиным прол абсолютно также
absolutely accurate Look, exactly the same way
абсолютно точно Смотри точно также как
Putin woke up was den the first year,
Путин проснулся были дено первый год
clear borders of states between
чёткие границы государств меж
states were in de no  interrupt me, don’t
государст были в де не перебивай меня не
interrupt me, the
перебивай
borders of the URSR and the RSFSR were E
сри тив границы урср и РСФСР были Е
200, look, they don’t burn, look, from the
200 смотри не подгорает смотри с де
first year until the beginning, the borders between the
первого года до перго границы между
republics were always there, yes,
республиками были они были всегда Да
Ukraine declared in the territory of the URSR, the
Украина провозгласила в территории урср
Russian Soviet Federative
Российская Советская Федеративная
Socialist Republic
Социалистическая Республика
declared independence
провозгласила независимость
within the borders of the RSFSR, and so these were the borders  Yes, they
в границах РСФСР так вот границы были Да
were then
были Потом де
demarcated, Yes, an
маркированы тиро Да были подписан
agreement on friendship and cooperation in the deno was signed  in the
договор о дружбе и сотрудничестве в дено
seventh year, where everything is recognized as borders by
седьмом году где всё признаны границах
treaties Yes, even so, never Yes,
договорами Да даже так вот никогда Да
none, and now in 2014
никакие и теперь 2014 год появляется
some Adolf Vladimirovich Putin appears Yes, and he
какой-то Адольф Владимирович Путин Да и
says, but we want to reconsider Crimea
говорит а мы хотим пересмотреть Крым
because Crimea doesn’t know when it was like that
потому что Крым фиг знает Когда был так
Ukraine says no and Putin says I was
Украина говорит нет и Путин говорит Меня
forced to attack  exactly the same with the Poles with
вынудили напасть точно тоже с поляками
Hitler, Putin really showed by this
Гитлером Путин реально вот этим показал
that he is exactly like Hitler, exactly like Hitler
что он точно как Гитлер точно как Гитлер
and brought the situation. If I wanted to
и ситуацию привёл Если бы я хотел
invent a situation, I damn sure wouldn’t have come up
придумать ситуацию Я бы блин не придумал
with Poland and  dank as he said but
с Польшей и данком так как он сказал но
Putin Well done he did it for us
Путин Молодец он сделал это за нас
really he compared himself to
реально он сравнил себя с
Hitler And you can’t say anything to this,
Гитлером И ты ничего на это не можешь
that is, your president
сказать то есть у тебя президент
supports burn that the victim is Poland who was
поддерживает гори что жертва Польша на
attacked Yes she is to blame She
которую напали Да она виновата Она
forced something in Nyurba  in the process
вынудила что-то на нюрбинском процессе
we will not see that Poland is to blame Show
мы не увидим что Польша виновата Покажи
me at least one document Yes, according to the results of the
мне хоть один документ Да по результатам
Second World War, where it is written that
Второй мировой войны где написано что
Poland was to blame for the attack on it,
Польша была виновата в нападении на неё
but in the
а
process of accusing Hitler, I’m
нука мнем процессе обвинения Гитлера
not surprised,
удиви не так
so let’s do it again  once
что давай-ка ещё раз
Crimea left Ukraine and became
Крым вышел из состава Украины и вошел в
part of
состав
Russia again look no matter Dansk
России ещё раз смотри неважно данск
entered too no look Dansk look
вошёл тоже нет смотри данск смотри ещё
again Dansk as a result of the First World
раз данск в результате первой мировой
War left Germany became
войны вышел из состава Германии вышл в
part of Poland Yes, Poland was formed,
состав Польши Да образовалась Польша всё
yes there is a peace treaty,
да есть мирный договор признаны
states are recognized, borders are recognized  Yes,
государства признаны границы Да
Adolf appears, he says, “Let’s say,
появляется Адольф говорит А давайте
once upon a time, something was the same there. And
когда-то что-то там было тоже самое И
then there is a state, there are borders,
тут есть государство есть границ
Vladimir Adolfovich appears,
появляется Владимир Адольфович
yes, he says, he says that wait, he says
да говорит говорит что подожди говорит
that  look Crimea There and so on
что смотри Крым Там и так дальше
dates You eat you call names You are podgora
даты Поешь ты обзываешься Ты подгора
because
потому что у
you have the most important argument you
тебя самый главный аргумент вы
justify Hitler your president the
оправдываете Гитлера ваш президент
president simply justifies Hitler and
президент просто оправдывает Гитлера и
you sit with a boring face and can’t do anything
ты со скучным лицом сидишь и ничего не
because you heard you
Потому что ты слышал тебе ещ раз
turn it on again to listen to how he  justifies
включить послушать как он оправдывает
Hitler. At first you pretended that you didn’t
Гитлера Ты сначала сделал вид что не
know. Yes, you knew everything. You
знал Да знал ты всё Ты же как русский
watched his interview like a Russian.
смотрел его интервью
That’s because
смотрел Вот так потому что
you, the whole world, the whole world is now helping
вы весь мир весь мир сейчас помогает
Ukraine. Why? Because Ukraine is
Украине Почему Потому что Украина
fighting  Nazism is carrying out
борется с нацизмом проводит
the denazification of
денацификация
the Federation, you
Федерации
understand, and that’s because you
понимаете и вот и потому что вы
really, well, it is, it’s a fact, it’s a fact,
реально ну это есть это факт это факт у
you already have a president who doesn’t hide his
вас уже президент не не скрывает свою
sympathy for Hitler, he says that Hitler
симпатию к Гитлеру он говорит что Гитлер
did the right thing by attacking Poland
правильно сделал что напал Польша его
forced Musiki to draw him like this
вынудила Мусики пририсовать вот так
Because you’re an unfortunate unfortunate  and we
Потому что ты несчастный несчастный и мы
are sending you,
тебя посылаем
let's go
пошёл
to the garage and immediately like this and what And
Давай под гараж а сразу такой а что А
how And where Putin will justify Nazism like this Yes,
как А где вот так Путин оправдает нацизм
I've prepared this thing for
Да я эю штуку
myself, I'll raise it further  Hello, I’m from
себе подем далее Здравствуйте я из
the city of Khmelnitsky Where am
города Хмельницкий Вы
I from? From
откуда я со
Smolensk, the Grand Duchy
Смоленска Великое княжество
of Lithuania, I don’t know, you know the history of Smolensk, this is
Литовское не знаю ты историю Смоленска
also Russia. Well, you know the history of
знаешь этоже Россия Ну ты знаешь историю
Smolensk. Yes, the original land
Смоленска Да исконная это какая земля
was what it was, well, Lithuania, let’s say, it was
была ч ну Литва допустим вот да
illegally seized by Russia. Why
незаконно захваченная Россией Ну почему
else is there some kind of kingdom of Moscow?  or a
ещ московским там какой-то царством или
principality yes Well, as long as you see Yes, soon I will
княжеством да Ну пока видишь Да скоро
recapture the Grand Duchy of Lithuania
Великое княжество Литовское отвоюю
Belarus Ukraine and
Белорусь Украина и
Lithuania will free you from the Moscow
Литва освободят вас от московского
yoke to liberate us From what, no, you
ига нас освобождать От чего хо не не ты
didn’t understand Smolensk, they won’t free you You’re
не понял Смоленск освободят не тебя Ты ж
not Rusich Why are you to Russia and Lithuania I
не Русич Почему ты к русси и к Литве
have nothing to do
Никакое отношения не имеешь
with the Russian people, what a native
я и русский человек какой исконно
Russian Well, you’re some kind of Tatar, I’m not  I know,
русский Ну ты какой-то татарин я не знаю
but by his face he’s a Tatar, no, where are your
но по лицу татарин да нет откуда твои
ancestors from? My ancestors are from Russia. Well, where are the
предки мои предки с России Ну откуда из
Chuvash Tatars from Russia? There are Bashkorts.
России вот татары Чуваши там башкорт э
Chechens are all Russia you're some kind of
чеченцы это всё Россия ты какой-то
Chechen not everyone from
чеченец не все
Moscow Moscow in Mosco in Moscow there
московские Московский в Моско в Москве
were no Slavs Tosya And where the Slavs the Slavs lived
было А где славяне славяне жили Вот
Look at the map just in Smolensk the
посмотри карту как раз в Смоленске ещё
Krivichi still lived and there were no Slavs in Moscow
жили да кривичи А в Москве уже никаких
There were no Merya tribes there
славян Не было там племена меря жили
Well  I speak Slavic and
Ну я разговариваю на славянском языке и
well, the Bulgarians, for example, look, the Bulgarians
что ну Болгары например смотри Болгары
came, they are a Turkic people. Yes, they came to the
пришли они тюркский народ Да пришли на
Balkans and  they started in Slavic and what do you
Балкан и начали по-славянски а что вы
want to say by this I want to say that
этим хотите сказать я хочу сказать что
you are just an occupier who is in the Smolensk
ты просто ну оккупант который на
region Yes, you have now come to the Holy Slavic land in large numbers
смоленщине Да на Святой славянской земле
and you live there Smolensk will
сейчас понаехал и живёшь там Смоленск
liberate
освободят
the Anglo-Saxons Yes they will liberate Smolensk from
англосаксов Да освободят Смоленск от
the occupation of half a century
оккупации полувековой
and a half thousand and
полутысячи и
that’s all And why I’m interested Why
всё А почему Вот мне интересно Почему
everything  WHY right now Why before this
все взб именно сейчас Почему до этого
before this you just didn’t
такого до этого просто не вам просто
care you didn’t listen to what we’re looking at
было пофиг вы не слушали что мы смотри
here’s the formula  world since the day of the year
ещё вот формула мира с дено пер года
known the world is not the absence of won the world
извест мир это не отсутствие воны мир
is the absence of Mosk
это отсутствие Моск
simply You have awakened only now you are
просто Вы пробудились только сейчас вы
now starting to dig your history and
сейчас начинаете копать свою историю и
understand why we Why we Well because
понимаешь почему мы Почему мы Ну потому
I What do I have to do with this
что я Какое отношение к этому имею
correctly then you are now beginning to
правильно то ты сейчас начинаешь
understand that you are
понимать что ты
just  not a Slav who speaks the
просто не славянин который говоришь на
Slavic language just like Kadyrov, he is
славянском языке так же как Кадыров он
not a Slav I’m not beginning to understand this
не славянин не начинаю это понимать
Look, that is, you don’t understand yet
Смотри а то есть ты ещё не понимаешь
You will need to explain the joke in
Тебе надо будет объяснить прикол в том
that I don’t understand your point of view You are
что и не пойму ваша точка зрения Вы
very strange  statements from this point of view of
очень странно высказы сю то зрения
language Yes, but he’s not Russian, it’s true
языке Да но он же не русский правда не
he’s not a Slav, he’s not Russian, he’s not a Slav, and
славянин он не русский он не славянин и
you speak Russian. But you’re not
ты говоришь на русском языке Но ты не
a Slav, you’re from Kady. Well, I was born in Russia,
славянин вы с Кады Ну я родился в России
which means I’m Russian by citizenship, and Kadyrov
значит я по гражданству рус и Кадыров
was born in Russia and by  by citizenship he is
родился в России и по гражданству он
Russian Well that all means he is Russian and
русский Ну всё значит он русский причём
no he is a Russian by citizenship you are
так нет он россиянин по гражданству вы
Russians Citizens of the Russian Federation
россияне Граждане Российской Федерации
Yes you are a Russian No not Russian look
Да ты россиянин Нет не русский смотри
Russian is  nationality Well, why should I
русский - это национальность Ну что мне
do a DNA test? I don’t have to do a DNA test,
ДНК тест делать ДНК тест можно не делать
like you can see that you’re not Russian Well,
типа тебе видно что ты не русский Ну
apparently you just started
видно просто на русском языке начал
speaking Russian Yes, the Slavic church language
говорить Да Славянский церковный язык
that was brought to you from Kiev was
который из Киева вам был при принесен
a little spoiled there by various other
немного испорчен там разными другими
influences Yes And these are the ones who taught me  the
влияниями Да И вот научили вот эти
tribes that lived there taught them to write to
племена которые там жили их учили писать
read like this, the Ukrainian language
читать так украинский язык от Русского
was formed from Russian No, not Ukrainian from Russian
образован Нет не украинский от Русского
Ukrainian from
украинский от
Old Slavic and Old Slavic from
древнеславянского а древнеславянский от
Russian no Ancient Slavs from
Русского нет Древне славянс от Русского
They are all Russian, they are all in Russian in terms of
так они все они все в русски перек плане
that Russian is from Old Slavic, that
что русский из древнеславянского что
Ukrainian is from Old Slavic Russian
украинский из древнеславянского русский
modern Russian we lived in different
современный ру мы жили на разных
territories I explain Russian and
территориях объясняю русский да
modern Russian well Why do
современный русский хорошо А почему вы
n’t you speak a foreign language everywhere
не разговариваете с ном языке везде
I explain because I am a Slav I can
объясняю потому что я славянин я могу
understand others  Slavs Yes, and I can
понимать других славян Да и могу
speak if I speak Ukrainian to a Pole, a
говорить если я буду с поляком говорить
Pole speaks Polish to me, I’ll
по украински поляк со мной по-польски я
understand him, you’re not a Slav if I speak
его пойму ты не славянин если я на своём
I’ll speak my Slavic language in Ukrainian,
славянском языке на украинском буду
you won’t understand me, well,
говорить ты же меня не поймёшь ну
say something, I took a towel and
скажите что-нибудь побу я взял рушницю и
a towel, I took it.
рушник я взял Ну рушницю что такое это
Well, what is a rushnytsia, is it some kind of sledgehammer? I don’t know. Well, I
кувалда какая-нибудь Я не знаю Ну вот я
took a towel and a towel, look, I’m in the
взял рушницю и рушник вот смотри я на
Slavic language  the Pole understands me the Czech
славянском языке поляк меня понимает чех
understands me I understand them, you don’t
меня понимает Я их понимаю ты не
understand No, they won’t understand you, they understand
понимаешь Нет они не поймут Вас понимают
Well, look, I did a man from Poland
Ну вот я смотри я делал человек с Польши
I say  with him in chat roulette
Я говорю с ним в чат рулетке
in Ukrainian, he is in Polish, I specifically
по-украински он по-польски я специально
and I understand from Slovaks I
и я понимаю со словаков
understand I understand all Slavic languages,
понимаю я понимаю все славянские языки
maybe not all the vocabulary because there is
не всю может лексику потому что есть
some vocabulary that is excellent, but I
некоторая лексика отличная но
understand most of it, look, give me a
большинство понимаю вот смотри давай
very simple test in the Slavic language
очень простой тест на славянском языке
and the
да
word Red  How will it be in Slavic languages
слово Red Как будет на славянских языках
red red in non-Slavic in
красный красный на не Славянском на
yours in all in Polish worms Yes, but
вашем во всех в польском червей Да а
Russian is not a Slavic language, look,
русский не славянский язык вот смотри
here you have it  Slavs want to say that
вот у вас поме славянс хоти сказать что
Russian is not a Slavic language Now,
русский не славянский язык Сейчас тебе
let's look now, I'll open
давай смотри сейчас вот я тебе открою
the sign for you,
табличку
look, they themselves wrote it
смотри кото сами написали
wrong now we have a very beautiful
так сейчас мы вот очень красивая есть
sign, so look,
табличек так вот смотри
uh, the Russian language is the word red And now
ээ русский язык слово красный А теперь
look, Ukrainian Chervony Belarusian
смотри украинский Червоный Белорусская
Chervony Polish Chervony Slovak
Червоный польская Червоный словацкая
Chervony  Czech Chervony and that
Червоный чешская Червоны и что
Slavic languages ​​Chervony you have red
славянские языки червны у вас красный
further Russian language
дальше русский язык
work Ukrainian Prat Belarusska praca
работа украинский Прат белорусска праца
Polska praca Slovak praci Czechska
Польска праца словака праци чешска
praci that only in the Russian language it’s not
праци что только в русском языке не так
like all the Slavs let’s say grove in Russian
как у всех славян давай так по-русски
you know what a grove of trees is Yes, but
роща знаешь что такое роща дерев Да но
you nevertheless speak
вы тем не менее разговаривайте на
Russian again, look again I and
русском языке ещё раз ещё раз смотри я и
I speak English and other
на английском разговариваю и на других
words that sound different in Russian
слова которые звучат на русском не так
than in
как на
others. Do you know that the same words
других Вы в курсе что такие же слова
can be found and that they also sound in Ukrainian
можно найти что на украинском звучат ещё
just look why these are all so
раз смотри почему вот эти все такие
basic here red Yes, this is a week
основные вот красный Да это вот неделя
Yes, let’s take the word week in Ukrainian
Да возьмём слово неделя в украинском
tizhden Belorussian tyn Polish tyn Slovak tizhden
тиждень Белорусско тынь Польска тынь
chek tyn hour here you have
словацко тиждень чека тынь час вот у вас
one
оди
hour godina godina godina godina godina for
час годына година година година година у
everyone one by one it was different for you
всех по одному было у вас по-другому
look, you have a towel, and
вот смотри полотенце у вас полотенце и
now we also have a towel, a towel, a towel, a towel,
что теперь у нас ещё рушник ручник ренч
I understand what you’re getting at. Well, so what now?
я понял к чему вы ведёте Ну и что теперь
look Why is your language, if it is
так вот смотри Почему ваш язык если он
Slavic, not similar to other Slavic
Славянский не похож на другие славянские
languages? Is it something? You see, yes. Well,
языки Я что что ли Вот видишь да Ну
look, Why am I a Slav, I understand other
смотри Почему я славянин понимаю других
Slavs without a translator, they understand me, they’re
славян без переводчика они меня понимают
just almost the same, it’s just that there
просто почти одинаковый вот просто не
was no imagination,
было фантазии
so they started to fuss and invent a
вот начали запаривать и придумывать
new language for themselves.
новый язык себе просто
Look, they took it from us from all the Slavs. So they
взяли смотри у нас у всех славян Вот они
understand each other and only the Russians don’t
понимают друг друга и только русские не
stupidly understand either the Poles or the Ukrainians or the
понимают тупо ни Поляков ни украинцев ни
Belarusians like Slaven or Chekhov. Why
белорусов типа ни Славен ни Чехов Почему
so Why?  well, Americans Well,
так А почему хорошо американцы Ну вот
let’s say they
допустим английским языком сейчас
all speak English now, they understand the whole world and
владеют все они понимают весь мир и что
now look again, explain If you are me,
теперь ещё раз смотри объясни Если вы я
I understand what and what Well,
я понимаю что и что вот Ну и что ещ раз
look again, I don’t understand what you’re getting at,
смотри я не понимаю к чему вы ведёте
Veta, you’re not Slavs, you’re just yes  different
Вете вы не славяне вы просто да разные
non-Slavic tribes who gave them
племена не славянские которые Им дали
part of the Slavic language and made an
часть Славянского языка и сделали
artificial Russian language out of it. Like you, there is
искусственный русский язык из Как и вы
no part, look, we have a natural language,
части нет смотри у нас природный язык у
it developed with us. So where did you
нас он развивался Так у вас откуда у вас
get it from?  this Russian language is where the tribes
взялся этот русский язык откуда племена
who started writing in Russian there came from
которые там начали писать по-русски
because there was a Church Slavonic language
потому что был церковнославянский язык
that was based on
такой да который был на основе
Old Bulgarian
староболгарская
And Church Slavonic is the
ский А церковнославянский так вот
Russian language, yes it
русский язык да он По большинству своему
came from Old
пошёл от староболгарская
Bulgarian for the most part. It was invented by Slavic from the very beginning.
Славянский придумал с самого начала
Let’s mean it wasn’t invented
Давайте В смысле придумал его не
came up with Oh, he developed in the process in the
придумал О он развивался в процес в
process of evolution where did he
процессе эволюции куда
run away? Let's roll
убежал Давайте по развитию откатится
back in development and just look, look,
назад и просто посмотрим вот смотри
when to that Type Come on when Why are
когда до того Типа Давай когда А зачем
you before me?  I don’t understand that what I want is
вы до меня я не понимаю что что я хочу
not you don’t do anything I’m just
не ты ничего не сделай я просто тебе
explaining to you that look after the liberation of
объясняю что смотри после освобождения
Smolensk yes yes what kind of liberation I do
Смоленска да да какой освобождение я не
n’t don’t want to be liberated so they don’t
не желаю освобождаться так тебя не
ask you we are liberating Smolensk you are
спрашивают мы Смоленск освобождаем ты
here you will run away look Anglo-Saxons
сюда ты ты убежишь смотри англосаксы
Slavs and Balts Lithuania Latvia Let them be
славяне и Балты Литва Латвия Да
liberated
освободят
our original lands are the lands of the Krivichi Yes you
исконно наши земли земли кривичи Да тебя
Yes you or if you yourself Well, we will give the
Да тебя либо если ты сам Ну мы дадим
right to leave on your own, this is what you have the
право уехать самому это такое ты имеешь
right  choose both for your primordial and there
право выбрать и на свои исконно и там
tribes Merya on Muscovite go to
племени меря на московщина поехать на
your lands yes or If you don’t
свои земли да либо Если ты будешь Э не
want to, a filter will be carried out to
хотеть будет проведена фильтрация
determine your trustworthiness or
определят твою благонадежность либо
deport or allow you to live without the
депортируют либо разрешат проживать без
right of citizenship That is, you will not be a
права гражданства То есть ты будешь не
citizen will have such a status, that is, and
гражданин будет такой статус то есть а
Crimea  those who are Crimea of ​​course Ukraine Everything is
Крым те кто Крым конечно Украина Тут всё
clear here like yes Crimea because also
понятно типа да Крым потому что ещё
Prince Vladimir Prince of Kiev where he
князь Владимир князь Киевский где он
received Baptism in  Chersonesos in the Crimea Yes,
принимал Крещение в херсонесе в Крыму Да
and there
и тмутараканское тмутараканское
was a Tmutarakan principality You know, but you don’t
княжество было Ты знаешь но ты же не
know because you are not a Slav, you don’t
знаешь потому что ты не славянин ты не
know the history of the Slavs Well, now
знаешь историю славян Ну а сейчас Почему
Why Why do you think that Crimea is yours if it is
Почему вы считаете что Крым ваш если он
even marked on the map Like Russia Show
даже на карте отмечен Как Россия Покажи
where Russia is marked on the map  Show the
где на карте отмечена Россия Покажи
Google map where it is marked Open I
Google карта где отмечена Открой я
opened the Google map you have
открывал Google карту у тебя есть
Alice No I have Alice You see Ask
Алиса Нет у меня Алиса Вот видишь Спроси
Alice whose Crimea she will
у Алисы чей Крым она тебе
tell you she will tell you  will say that along the borders this is
скажет она скажет что по границам - это
Russia No, he won’t tell you, Alice won’t
Россия Нет не скажет вот Алиса тебе не
tell you that Crimea is Russia I bet Well,
скажет что Крым - это Россия Спорим Ну
maybe it’s your Ukrainian So don’t
может быть это ваша украинская Так не
say no, your Alice, come on, ask, Anya
говори нет твоя Алиса давай вот спроси
nett Ali, I understand Yes, now
есть Аня нетт Али поня Да сейчас
wait for me Well, okay, I’ll open the tab  I’ll
подождите я Ну ладно я открою вкладку
type So be Alice Type Yes, why do
наберу Так уж быть Алису Набери Да зачем
I need Alice? I’ll just open the map right now
мне Алиса я сейчас прямо карту открою
What
просто Какую
map is the world map by
карту карта мира по
country on some site, draw it, take
странам на каком-то сайте нарис возьми
Google Yes, I’ll just  Yandex pictures
Google Да я просто Яндекс картинки
opened the pictures so whatever you want
открыл картинки так там что хочешь Может
in the pictures Maybe you can draw it shorter in the pictures
в картинках быть ты нарисуешь короче
No, you know What does Crimea have to do with everything here, it’s
Да нет знаете Причём тут везде Крым это
Russia is strange Where are you running away?
Россия странно Куда ты убегаешь да Мы те
through skarg ODS in your ban and even
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
more videos you don’t show people sometimes you don’t
багато вдео не показуе людям вчасно не
show information about  streams for
показуе информация про стримы тому для
you, we are writing an operational link
тоб мы оперативный звязок пишиться прямо
right now and while there in telegra okm video sche
зараз а пок там в телегра окм видео ще
tezh tsikava and korisna information and we are
теж цикава и корисна информация и мы
guilty of you trimati postiyny
повинни з вами тримати постийний
operational link is independent in that chi
оперативный звязок незалежно в того чи
show you the process YouTube Glory to Ukraine
покаже вам проце YouTube Слава украини
writing
пись а